Imogene Myrland Papers 1936-1974
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Imogene Myrland Papers, 1936-1974
AZ 442
Correspondence, photographs, clippings, financial records, scrapbooks, teaching aids, miscellaneous publications, and other material relating to the organization and development of nursery schools and day care centers in Arizona, especially Tucson.
Myrland, Imogene J.
2.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Educator, Tucson, Arizona; began with setting up nursery schools under the WPA in 1936, organized and directed the Tucson Nursery School in 1946.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, photographs, clippings, financial records, scrapbooks, teaching aids, miscellaneous publications, and other material relating to the organization and development of nursery schools and day care centers in Arizona, especially Tucson. Also includes personal and biographical material; correspondence about and from parent education groups in Tucson, State Child Care Committee of the Arizona Defense Council, 1941-1944, and the Arizona State 4-C Committee, 1970; and scrapbooks of various local nursery schools.
Access Terms
Arizona. Governor's Advisory Committee on Community Coordinated Child Care
Tucson Nursery School
Bisbee Nursery School
Carillo Nursery School (Tucson, Ariz.)
Nursery schools -- Arizona -- Tucson
Nursery schools -- Arizona
Preschool teachers -- Arizona
Day care centers -- Arizona
Day care centers -- Arizona -- Tucson
Education, Preschool -- Arizona
Parenting -- Study and teaching -- Arizona -- Tucson
Children -- Arizona
Correspondence
Photographs
Container List
- Tucson Nursery Schools correspondence. 1939-1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Tucson Nursery Schools clippings. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Tucson Nursery Schools clippings. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Tucson Nursery Schools miscellaneous notes, lists, and records. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Tucson Nursery Schools miscellaneous printed items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Tucson Nursery School, 345 S. 4th Ave. photographs. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Tucson Nursery School, 345 S. 4th Ave. photographs. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs of various nursery schools: Tucson. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photographs of various nursery schools in Southern Arizona. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Nursery school photographs not fully identified. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Arizona nursery schools history, lists, statistics, etc. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Nursery school guidelines, Philosophy, programs, forms, etc. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Nursery school menus. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Imogene Myrland's Program Outline for Nusery Schools. 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Imogene Myrland's Handbook for Child Care Centers. 1938, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Nursery schools and day care centers miscellaneoud publications. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Parent Education Program, District # 1. 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Parent Education Program, District # 1. 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Parent education for Spanish speaking mothers, miscellaneous materials. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Arizona Civilian Defense Council, State Child Care Committe. 1941-1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Licensing of day care centers. 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Arizona State 4-C Committee. 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Imogene Myrland miscellaneous and personal material. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Imogene Myrland awards, memberships, and retirement party. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Imogene Myrland photographs. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Tucson nursery schools newspaper publicity and radio scripts. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Tucson nursery schools Audits. 1955-1956, 1958-1960, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Statewide nursery schools' inventories. 1943 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Southern Arizona Nurseries" scrapbook. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Bisbee Nursery School" scrapbook. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- "Carillo Nursery School" scrapbook. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Teaching Child Guidance to Spanish-Speaking Parents poster book. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Parent education teaching aids and photographs; WPA nursery poster. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- "WPA Central Arizona Nursery" scrapbook compiled by Annie M. Kidd. 1936-1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)